THE NEW YORK STATE TENANTS & NEIGHBORS COALITION RECORDS (APAP198) 1970-2002
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Communications, 1973-2000, Undated; 5; 4.4
  - Mayoral Forum of New York City, 2001 July 18 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - New York City Coalition to End Lead Poisioning- Press Packet, 2002 November 14 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The Park West Tenant, 2002 June (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Lawyers Alliance for New York Newsletter, 2002 Summer (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Rent 2002- Campaign Materials (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Northwest Bronx Community and Clergy Coalition, Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Myths and Facts about Rent Control, Undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Tenant's Manual to Fighting Arson, Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Audio Visual Materials, 1973-2000, Undated; 6; 1.5
  The Audio Visual Materials series is arranged chronologically.
  The Audio Visual Materials series contains videotapes with the Tenants and Neighbors Show, NAHT Conferences and other rallies/picketing and politician speeches. Eight U-Matic tapes of the Tenants & Neighbors show is also included within this series.
  - Inside Albany, 1987 May 10; 1987 May 17 (Video-tape 1)
  - Inside Albany, 1992 May 17 (Video-tape 2)
  - Morris & Carrick NYS Democratic Committee "Protect", 1997 April 25 (Video-tape 3)
  - Morris & Carrick New Yorkers to Save Rent Protection "Disaster", 1997 May 14 (Video-tape 4)
  - Governor Pataki Rent Speech, 1997 May 15 (Video-tape 5)
  - Albany Rally Volcanic Video, 1997 May (Video-tape 6)
  - Rent War: Road to City Hall/ On the Line, 1997 May (Video-tape 7)
  - Governor Pataki, Senator Bruno, Member of Assembly Silver: Events in Room 250/ The Capital, 1997 June 15-16 (Video-tape 8)
  - Morris & Carrick New Yorkers to Save Rent Protection "Countdown", 1997 June (Video-tape 9)
  - Rent Wars, 1997 June (Video-tape 10)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Con-Con # 1, 1997 October (Video-tape 11)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Rent Controlled Tenants The Forgotten Minority # 2, 1997 November (Video-tape 12)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show # 3, 1997 December (Video-tape 13)
  - Tenants & Neighbors: Money, Style, and Power, 1997 (Video-tape 14)
  - Rent Campaign 1997 (Video-tape 15)
  - Waffle Breakfast in Albany and Office Interviews, 1998 January 06 (Video-tape 16)
  - "Hells Kitchen Fights Developers", 1998 January 21 (Video-tape 1)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: The Leo house # 5, 1998 Febrauary (Video-tape 2)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: How to Survive Housing Court # 6, 1998 March (Video-tape 3)
  - The Tenant & Neighbors Show: SRO Tenants Unite! # 7, 1998 April (Video-tape 4)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Holding HUD Accountable # 8, 1998 May (Video-tape 5)
  - Picket Pataki, 1998 June (Video-tape 6)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: The 1998 Rent Hike Rip Off # 9, 1998 June (Video-tape 7)
  - Tenants and Neighbors Video, 1998 June (Video-tape 8)
  - NAHT Conference Part 1, 1998 June (Video-tape 9)
  - NAHT Conference Part 2, 1998 June (Video-tape 10)
  - NAHT Conference Part 3, 1998 June (Video-tape 11)
  - T & N Shows, 1998 July (Video-tape 12)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Guiliani's Rent Guide # 10, 1998 July (Video-tape 13)
  - Michael McKee on "Good Day", 1998 August 16 (Video-tape 14)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Tenants to D.C.: Save Our Homes # 11, 1998 August (Video-tape 15)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: The Pitfalls of Subletting # 12, 1998 September (Video-tape 16)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: The 1997 Rent Law- One Year Later # 13, 1998 September (Video-tape 1)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: The Rent 2000 Campaign # 14, 1998 October (Video-tape 2)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Tenant Power at the Ballot Box # 15, 1998 November (Video-tape 3)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Leo House Tenants Evicted The Struggle Continues # 16, 1998 December (Video-tape 4)
  - Tuesday- D. C. Demonstration, 1998 (Video-tape 5)
  - Rent Guidelines Board, 1998 (Video-tape 6)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Housing Court- Worse and Worse # 17, 1999 February (Video-tape 7)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show:Loft Tenants at Risk # 18, 1999 March (Video-tape 8)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Mitchell-Lama at the Chopping Block # 19, 1999 April (Video-tape 9)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Public Housing Saved From Drowning # 20, 1999 May (Video-tape 10)
  - R & B Raw Footage, 1999 May (Video-tape 11)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Taking albany By Storm # 23, 1999 June (Video-tape 12)
  - Tenants & Neighbors, 1999 September 7 (Video-tape 13)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Pitfalls of Subletting # 24, 1999 October (Video-tape 14)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Get the Lead Out # 25, 1999 October (Video-tape 15)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Dangerous Landlord Loopholes # 26, 1999 December (Video-tape 16)
  - Mitchell-Lama Lobby Day, 1999 (Video-tape 1)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Will the City Council Shaft Tenants # 27, 2000 January (Video-tape 2)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show:Loft Law Meets Quick Draw # 28, 2000 Febraury (Video-tape 3)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: # 29, 2000 Febraury (Video-tape 4)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Mitchell-Llama Fights Back # 30, 2000 Febraury (Video-tape 5)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show:Rent 2000: Victory for Tenants # 31, 2000 April (Video-tape 6)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: HUD Tenants Getting It Together # 32, 2000 May (Video-tape 7)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Sublet Guide # 12/24, 2000 July (Video-tape 8)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Renting and Raving # 33, 2000 July (Video-tape 9)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show:Landlords and the Big Lie # 34, 2000 July (Video-tape 10)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: The Sublet Guide # 12/24, 2000 August (Video-tape 11)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: A Bounty on Tenants Heads # 35, 2000 October (Video-tape 12)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Pitaki's Sneak Attack on Tenants # 36, 2000 November (Video-tape 13)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: The Lead Law: A Year Later # 37, 2000 November (Video-tape 14)
  - Dangers of Primary Residence Decontrol, 2001 January (Video-tape 15)
  - Pataki Trashes Tenant Rights, 2001 February 01 (Video-tape 16)
  - The High Income Decontrol Trap, 2001 Febraury (Video-tape 1)
  - Tenants & Neighbors, 2001 May 02 (Video-tape 2)
  - Owner Use Eviction, 2001 July 03 (Video-tape 3)
  - Rent 2002 Campaign, 2001 December 14 (Video-tape 4)
  - Tenant Association Meeting in Washington D.C., 2002 June (Video-tape 5)
  - Rally March, 2002 June (Video-tape 6)
  - 90 Days- Documentary, Undated (Video-tape 7)
  - "Hot Line" # 1 with Sam Himmelstein, Undated (Video-tape 8)
  - Leo House Tenants Evicted- The Fight Continues, Undated (Video-tape 9)
  - PBS Frontline- Other Peoples Money, Undated (Video-tape 10)
  - Rent Guidelines Hearing, Undated (Video-tape 11)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: # 29, 2000 March (Video-tape 1)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Mitchell- Llama Fights Back # 30, 2000 April (Video-tape 2)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Rent 2000: Victory for Tenants # 31, 2000 May (Video-tape 3)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: HUD Tenants Getting it Together # 32, 2000 June (Video-tape 4)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Renting and Raving # 33, 2000 July (Video-tape 5)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: The Sublet Guide # 12/24, 2000 August (Video-tape 6)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: Pitfalls of Subletting # 35, 2000 September (Video-tape 7)
  - The Tenants & Neighbors Show: The Lead Law: A Year Later # 37, 2000 December (Video-tape 8)
- National Housing Issues, 1973-2000, Undated; 7; 1.8
  The National Housing Issues series is arranged chronologically.
  The National Housing Issues series focuses on renters' issues from a national perspective. Much of the materials come from the National Alliance of HUD Tenants as well as the Low Income Housing Information Service.
  - Department of Housing and Urban Development- Title 24, Chapter IV, Part 403 Materials, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - National Committee for Rent Control - Fact Sheets, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - National Housing Law Project- Security Deposit Packet, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Washington, D.C. Housing Statistics, Uniformed Planned Community Act, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Enterprise Zone Legislation and U.S. Congressman Jack Kemp- Housing Resolutions, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Housing and Urban Development (HUD) Materials, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - National Housing Law Project- Legislative Update on House Authorization Bill, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Low Income Housing Information Service, 1983-1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Low Income Housing Information Service, 1984-1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Housing at Risk: Expiring Federal Subsidies, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Housing at Risk: Expiring Federal Subsidies, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - National Housing Law Project: State and Local Iniatives to Preserve Subsized Rental Housing, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Northeast States: Proposals on Federal Incentives Needed to Preserve Assisted Housing, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Community Service Society- Papers on National Housing Issues, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Congressional Record- House, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - HUD Tenant Alerts, 1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Low Income Housing Information Service- Pamphlets, 1990-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - National Affordable Housing Act- Agency Questions, 1990; 1991; Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - National Affordability Housing Act- Supprt Materials, 1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - On Your Mark, Get Set, Take Control: A Guide for Residents About the First Nine Months of the Title 6 Program, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - National Housing and Urban Developments- National Low Income Housing Coalition, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - NYS Tenants & Neighbors Coalition National Memoranda, 1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - National Alliance of HUD Tenants, 1997 July (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - National Alliance of HUD Tenants, 1997 August (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Report on S. 462 the Public Housing Reform & Responsibility Act of 1997, 1997 August (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - National Alliance of HUD Tenants, 1997 September (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - National Alliance of HUD Tenants, 1997 October (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - National Alliance of HUD Tenants, 1997 November- December (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - National Alliance of HUD Tenants, 1999 January-March (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - National Alliance of HUD Tenants, 1999 April-June (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - National Alliance of HUD Tenants, 1999 July-August (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Memo to Members: The Weekly Newsletter of the National Low Income Housing Coalition, 1999 September-December (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - National Alliance of HUD Tenants, 1999 September-December (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - National Alliance of HUD Tenants, 2000 January-March (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - National Alliance of HUD Tenants, 2000 April-August (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - National Alliance of HUD Tenants- Nassau County, 2000 April-December (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - National Alliance of HUD Tenants, 2000 September-December (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - National Alliance of HUD Tenants, 2001 January-April (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - National Alliance of HUD Tenants, 2001 May-August (Box 3, Folder 7)
- News Clippings, 1973-2000, Undated; 8; 0.4
  The News Clippings series is arranged chronologically.
  The News Clippings series represents Tenants & Neighbors voice in the press. Much of it is Op Ed pieces written by Michael McKee. The bulk of the materials is from 1997, focusing on rent decontrol. Various rent protest and rallies that Tenants & Neighbors participated in or organized are also found in this series.
  - News Clippings, 1970-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - News Clippings, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - News Clippings, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - News Clippings, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - News Clippings, 2001; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)